Srivatsan Thumati Balaji

Full Stack Developer

srivatsantb@gmail.com

+917845774670

kryptocodes.github.io

Profile

I am a young and driven Full Stack Developer with 2+ years of experience, DevOps and system administration experience alongside. I have successfully deployed and maintained multiple web apps with large userbases as well as contributed to open source projects and continue to do so.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript (TypeScript), Python,C,C++,Bash

Frameworks: React, Next, Node, Express, React Native, Django

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis

Tools & Technologies: Git, GitHub, GitLab, Babel

DevOps: AWS, Docker, SSH, Ngnix

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Experience

Lead Web Developer and Co Founder FOSS CLUB

September 2018 - Present

Built and maintained internal websites using React. Extended internal front-end component library in React with Styled Components

Full Stack Developer Freelance

October 2020 - Present

Designed UI Logic and data structure, Created a fully functional React SPA with Node JS (GraphQL and PostgreSQL). Implemented service workers to make it a PWA usable offline

Web Developer Remote Intern Project42L

July 2020 - August 2020

Built websites using Wagtail (Django), React and bootstrap

Projects

LiReddit

November 2020 - Current

LiReddit is similar to site like Reddit or HackerNews you subscribe to forums you're interested in, post links and discussions, then vote, and comment on them.

Technology Stack

TypeScript,GraphQL,URQL,Node JS, PostgreSQL,TypeORM,Redis,Next JS

https://github.com/kryptocodes/lireddit_frontend

Gate Pass Management System

April 2020 - August 2020

A Complete CMS System, which allows a resident student to apply for his/her Gate Pass Online also generates QR Code when the concerned authority approves the pass. With Four different role dashboard integrated with notification support and offline PWA.

Technology Stack

MongoDB, Mongoose ODM,Express, Node JS, React

https://github.com/kryptocodes/GPMS_backend

https://github.com/kryptocodes/GPMS_frontend

Education

Amrita College of Engineering and Technology - Nagercoil, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Expected May 2022

Kendriya Vidyalaya - Madurai May 2018